So for me,
对我来说
as an entrepreneur, what are the type of design types that I need to care about?
作为一个企业家 我需要注意哪些类型的设计呢？
>> So my specialty is interaction design,
我的专业是互动设计
so as you've probably guessed from me saying task, task, task over and
所以你大概能够理解我之前几分钟一直重复地说
over again for the last few minutes, that's where I bias towards.
任务、任务、任务 这是我的偏向
So kind of we focus on trying to understand users and behaviors.
我们致力于了解用户及其行为
Think about the types of things that they want to do, and
想想他们想要做哪些事情
how to best fulfill them.
我们如何尽量地满足他们
Now that's just one of the specializations.
这只是其中一个专业
There's many.
其实分很多类型
Other very common ones are visual design.
非常常见的一种就是视觉设计
They focus on everything
他们主要负责用户与产品互动时
that the user sees while they're engaging with your experience.
看见的所有东西
>> Is there like, colors, and stuff like that, or?
比如说颜色 或者类似的东西？
>> Colors is one, but it's also things like layout, like scale,
颜色是其中一种 还有排版 比例
any iconography that's there, everything from fonts and
插图 还有字体
upward, anything that becomes a pixel in that piece of software.
上方标题栏 任何构成软件像素的东西
>> Right. >> Visual design
— 是的 — 视觉设计
tries to concentrate on that.
主要是针对这些的
And there's thousands of small decisions that go into that,
在这个专业上
that is their specialization.
需要做成千上万的小决定
Then there's also things like motion design.
还有比如动态设计
This is a newer focus for design in many cases.
这是很多案例的新关注点
And they're concerned with how anything animates, big or small.
动态设计主要涉及到如何让画面上无论大小的东西更有生气
To give the user a sense that their feedback is being heard, and
要让用户感觉到他们的反馈有人接收了
that the system's responding to it.
系统也做出了反应
And just to kind of bring the to life a little bit.
让画面更加栩栩如生
They make it feel like it's something they're really kind of engaging in.
让他们感觉到他们真正地在与它互动
This push and pull way.
以这种推拉的方式
>> You can also stress things with animation, right?
你还可以通过动画强调一些东西 对吧？
>> Absolutely.
确实如此
Animation is a great way to tell the user where their
动画可以清晰地告诉用户
attention should be focused at any given time.
在某个时刻他们应该关注什么地方
And then there's other specializations.
另外还有一些专业
There's things like Industrial design, the design of physical objects.
像工业设计、实物设计
>> Right. >> There's sound design, there's conran,
— 是的 — 还有声音设计、像 Conran 的概念
or print design, and so on and so on and so on.
或者是画册设计 等等 等等
Anything that you're doing on this product that has
无论你负责产品的什么部分
some decision that needs to be made, there's probably
都需要做一些决定
a whole discipline of design that can help you make that decision.
但可能各种设计专业可以帮助你做决定
>> So what you're basically telling me is that I need to hire eight people?
所以你的意思是我需要聘用八个人？
>> Yes.
是的
Wait, no, no.
等等 不是 不是
You can get by with fewer.
你可以雇佣更少的人
>> Okay. >> So I know most small teams just don't
— 好的 — 我知道有一些比较小型的团队
have that capacity to hire out all the specializations.
没有能力雇佣全部专业
So the good news is that, in my experience, most designers are hybrids.
但是有一个好消息是 以我的经验来说 大部分设计师都是混合型的
They might identify as being one of those specializations, but they often
他们可能属于某个专业的设计师
have familiarity to varying degrees with the other fields of the discipline.
但不同程度地熟悉其他的一些领域
So what's important to keep in mind when you hire
所以 在招聘的时候 你需要记住的是
is kind of have a sense of what your expectations are going to be.
你要清楚你的期望是什么
What are you going to need out of this designer?
你需要这名设计师做什么？
Do you need interaction and visual?
是需要互动还是视觉？
Do they need to work on your brand for you?
需要涉及你的品牌么？
And make sure that the capabilities are in the people that you hire.
确保雇佣的人有你想要的能力
Or, make sure that they are comfortable directing the work of contractors who
或者说 如果你与拥有你缺乏的能力的承包商合作
might be able to kind of augment the capabilities that they lack.
要确保他们能够很好地引导承包商工作
>> How do they know if they're any good?
你怎么知道他们好不好呢？
>> [LAUGH] Wow, that's a good question.
问得好
I think the best way to judge a designer is from their work.
我认为评判一个设计师最好的方法是观察他们的作品
So you should certainly ask for work samples.
你肯定会问他们要一些工作样品
You should look for the portfolio.
看看他们的代表作品集
You should find out what kind of things get them excited about design.
要找到他们对设计的什么东西感兴趣
>> Right.
是的
>> Are they very focused on the user and on simplicity?
他们的注意力是在用户 还是简洁性？
Are they a designer who can come in and give more pizzazz, a little sex appeal,
他们是不是能够给产品带来活力
a little gloss to the product?
魅力、光彩？
There's appeal to having all those types of people involved with the work.
这就要求工作中拥有所有类型的人才